>> Jem Young: 因此查找查找文件的工作，但如果您想执行某些操作
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: So find works for finding
files but what if you want to do some
你想看看里面的文件吗
sort of introspection,
you want to look inside a file?
我们用 grep ， grep 是，很多人不喜欢
We use grep, and grep is,
a lot of people don't like it because
很多人不喜欢正则表达式
a lot of people don't
like regular expressions.
他们说如果你有问题需要用正则表达式
They say if you have a problem and
you need to use a regular expression,
现在你有两个问题，绝对是真的。
now you have two problems,
which is absolutely true.
[ LAUGH] 还有一个随机编程提示。
[LAUGH] And a random programming tip.
如果您是代码中的正则表达式，请注释该正则表达式
If you are regular expressions in your
code, comment what that regular expression
是我向你保证当你想出来的时候别人可能不会
is, cuz I promise you while you figure
it out, someone else probably won't.
这就像一个普通公民的小费。
And it's just like a tip for
just being a good citizen.
但是格雷普我们要用一些正则表达式
But grep,
we're gonna use some regular expressions.
我们不会太深的因为可能有个问题
We are not gonna go too deep into them
because there's probably a course on
正则表达式，并且它们会变得非常，很脏。
regular expressions, and
they can get really, really nasty.
有人知道高尔夫是什么代码吗
Anybody know what code golf is?
>> Jem Young: 是你有问题的地方，然后贴在
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: It's where you have
a problem, and then you post it on
有人说我要用最短的密码来解决这个问题
the internet, and someone says I'm gonna
solve this in the shortest amount of code,
几乎总是有人把正则表达式和
and almost invariably someone
puts the regular expressions and
他们有时候会喜欢书页
they get like pages long sometimes.
你可以和他们玩很多但这不是我的书呆子
And you can have a lot of fun with them
but that's not the way I nerd out.
我对快速和疯狂的部落感到不安
I nerd on the Fast and Furious trivia.
是真的我知道
It's true, I do.
比如说你知不知道在第一个快法和富丽华，
For instance, did you know in
the first Fast and Furious,
他们的车都没有后视镜吗
they don't have any rear-view
mirrors in any of their cars?
你可能没注意到因为他们从不回头
You probably didn't notice that
because they never look back.
我没开玩笑好吧
I'm not kidding, okay.
[ LAUGH] 在 Netflix 上看 Fast 和 Furhous。
[LAUGH] Go on Netflix watch The Fast and
the Furious.
如果我在那我们就会坐到一边去
If I were there, we'll sit aside.
但你不必这么做我只是想在今天得到温暖
But you don't have to, I'm just
trying to get warmed up for today.
但 grep 是我们已经用过的东西之一
But grep is one of the things
that we've used already.
其实我们打字输的时候用它 grep 看过去
In fact, we use it when we're typing
output through and grep just looks over
所有这些代码的每一行都在寻找我们想要找到的东西
every single line of that code, and
looks for what we're trying to find.
如果你想看一个文件
And if you want to look inside a file, and
这实际上是一个很棒的实用程序， zgrep 搜索 gzip 文件。
this is actually an awesome utility,
zgrep search inside of gzip files.
因为随着时间的推移，日志文件会自动在 gzip中并置。
Because over time, log files
automatically get concatenated in gzip.
你就像去年 12 月 23 日发生的事吗
You're here like,
what happened December 23rd of last year?
您可以找到该日志文件，该文件将被压缩，并且您可以使用 zgrep
You could find that log file, which is
gonna be minified, and you can use zgrep
在里面进行搜索而不是把它解包然后再穿过它
and search inside it rather than having
to unpack it and then run through it.
所以，让我们在 grep上做个简单的练习。
So let's do a quick exercise on grep.
>> Jem Young: 如果您的节点进程正在运行，那么让我们执行 ps。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: And if your node
process is running, let's do ps.
因此，为了显示正在运行的进程，我们正在传递一些参数。
So to show the running process,
we're passing some arguments.
aux 显示所有进程。
aux is show all of the processes.
其实我在这里的笔记里有
Actually, I have it in my notes here.
显示所有用户的流程，显示流程所有者，
Show the process for all the users,
display the process owners,
然后显示未在终端 AKA中运行的进程
and then show processes that are not
running in the terminal, AKA,
在后台运行的进程。
processes that are running
in the background.
并且您应该有一个进程正在运行，因为如果您的服务器已启动并正在运行，
And you should have a process running
because if your server is up and running,
快速服务器已启动并正在运行，意味着节点正在运行。
the express server is up and running,
and that means Node is running.
我现在就这么做了明白了
So I'm gonna do that now, clear.
我们得用重定向运算符 grep 节点来处理
ps aux, we got to pipe that with
the redirection operator, grep node.
在那里，我有一个节点进程正在运行。
And there we go,
I have a node process running.
这就是你脑海中最重要的事情之一
This is one of these things that
keep at the top of your mind
如果你一直在做很长很长的日志文件
if you're ever running through a long,
long log file.
Grep 是寻找事物的最快途径，而不是手动遍历每一个
Grep is the fastest way to find something
rather than manually traversing every
单行。
single line.
让我们做点小点的吧格雷普
Let's try do a little,
just pipe this, grep.
事实上让我看看有什么好的
Actually, let me see what's
something good to grep for.
我要找每一个我登录的例子，所以我管它，然后是 grep then jem.
I'll look for every instance that I
logged in so I pipe that, grep then jem.
我们走吧
Here we go.
这里是我登录或登录的每个实例
And here's every instance
where I logged in or
做了一些需要苏多人同意的事情
did something that
requires sudo permission.
现在，如果我真的很聪明，我不是，但如果我比我聪明得多，
Now, if I was really clever, and I'm not,
but if I was much more clever than me,
表示 jem 2.0，我将创建正则表达式
say jem 2.0,
I would create a regular expression for
未经授权的人，我可以把这个名单拿上，去拿 IP 地址。
everybody that was unauthorized, I can
take that list and grab the IP addresses.
那就管那些被禁止的名单
Then pipe those to a banned list.
最伟大的是我们现在有能力做到这一点。
And the great thing is we now have
those capabilities of doing that.
我们可以把它们写在一个日志文件中
We could write them to a log file,
separate log file,
就像邪恶的 IP 日志文件之类的
which are like evil IP log file or
something like that.
我们可以在命令行的 3 个或 3 个
And we can do that all in
the command line in three or
命令上的四个步骤非常强大
four steps on the command,
which is really powerful.
我知道，我们正在安顿下来，我开始变得更兴奋
I know, [LAUGH] we're settling in and I'm
starting to get a bit more excited about
我们今天要学的东西
all the things we're going to learn today.
我们所学到的一切
All the things we have learned already.